Alright poor people, I'm back.
That's right.
Here to provide you my worldly wisdom on how to become successful and make some serious money out of it.
And the first thing to understand is whatever it is you're doing, just stop.
You may have noticed I've stopped.
doing anything productive over the past few months I haven't released a single video.
because I just realized that it's just totally pointless to try to do anything.
nowadays when the government is printing
Inflating massive amounts of money right like you're actually
trying to earn your dough and then the government is just printing...
billions, trillions of dollars out there just
making this money out of thin air to dilute your work.
They're just extracting.
all of your value.
So why even bother?
Why try?
It's a lot like being on the Titanic and then trying to...
study java while the ship is sinking or rearranging chairs doing your LeetCode and just stop.
It's over.
I know we
We all feel this need to try to be productive, work hard, hustle, grind.
were addicted to the pain, the struggle of putting in the hard work but
Sometimes you mistake motion for action.
And in this world of ADHD, the best thing you can do, the contrarian move,
is to just do nothing.
Just stop moving.
Can anybody just do that?
Hold still.
because the more you move the more energy you're going to waste and the faster you're going to die you're wasting your own resources
You're going to have to pay more for food.
So you may be wondering what's new.
Nothing.
Absolutely nothing is new.
around here, I've been sitting around doing nothing just staring at the blank screen all day.
because there's no work to do, really, except to just wait.
I'm waiting for Bitcoin to get to a million dollars actually because it's my only salvation around here.
is the only thing that can save me.
I've recognized that fact whereas you have not.
Many people have not.
and they're still out there pretending, trying to struggle.
Trying to do something just to keep themselves busy.
You can work.
or not, doesn't really matter, it's really optional.
It's not going to move the needle here though.
The most important thing when you're syncing on the Titanic ship is really your positioning.
You'll want to get to a life raft if at all possible because the whole ship is done.
And look, I get it, I've been gone for a while, and you may be under the impression that
I've just been slacking off around here with the lack of any new video content.
You may think that I've just been hiking the mountain.
Hawaiian islands, going on Mexican cruises, or exploring Japan like I am now.
and what I suppose you would be right.
but you would be highly mistaken to think that I'm
unproductive.
In fact, I've been more productive
than I've ever been in my whole entire life, more productive than most programmers certainly, what have I been doing?
I have been huddling, diamond handing.
which is an incredibly difficult skill because it requires
me to read news, reread news, and continue to convince myself
to just sit still and do nothing instead of
trading, buying, selling, getting in and out of positions.
Sometimes the best thing to do is to
just do nothing.
And yes, that is considered to work as well.
It's not about how hard you work,
about how smart you are.
Don't be addicted to your own
pain and suffering, it is not required and certainly not the prerequisite to success.
by any means.
In fact, the path to success is often fun and easy.
Have you ever noticed how everyone seems to tell you to work hard, grind harder,
put in the hours, wake up early, but nobody ever tells you what to actually
work on except to maybe go to the gym and somehow this is going to
and make you successful.
Because nobody knows what to actually do, there's nothing to do.
There's no actual work.
For anyone to do a round trip, what do you want me to do?
Build you a little app?
Some little stupid minigame, in-game monetization, microtransactions, you want me to make you a blog?
Good luck.
This idea of work was really a figment of the last era.
But hard work never equals success.
You see, I know you.
I understand you, you programmer tech bros out there.
disgusting know-it-all scumbags
We're the same.
Actually, we're not.
I'm way better.
The world is now flooded with computer science degrees.
Everyone's got one.
computer science graduates have tripled within the last decade and companies are now laying everybody off
because they just don't need these useless degrees anymore and what's really happened actually is...
We've moved on from the knowledge economy.
rationality, merit, science.
None of these things really matter anymore in today's era.
Actually, we're entering this post-science, late-stage capitalism era where
Mostly it's just about power, if you have power
then you get what you want and screw the science right ignore that
manipulate the data.
By now people have realized how to game the system in order to achieve the result.
that they desire.
And beyond that what's really happened is I believe we have reached peak
technology, actually.
We invented what is essentially digital drugs, digital opioids.
which is like short form video, TikToks.
And that has really obsoleted the need for
any future technological innovation.
People don't need anymore apps or games when they've become
What more do digital drug addicts need?
After all, they're totally content with
doing in front of their videos.
These short videos and TikToks really provide people with everything.
They tell them how to think,
what to do, where to go, what to buy.
And so what's happened is, even with something as innovative as Apple's Vision Pro,
VR goggles with all of that technology.
nobody even cares anymore because we
We've moved on past the knowledge economy, we are now in an...
attention economy were the number one skill.
is not STEM.
Nobody cares about STEM.
The number one skill is your ability to gain attention.
to draw attention in this world.
If you're able to do that, you'll be able to succeed in the new attention economy.
If you can't.
If all you know is some STEM degree, science or something, then you're going to fail.
Nobody cares.
that the science doesn't even matter nobody cares
about the science is totally fabricated.
Nobody believes any of the science or data or
any of their research papers, science has become a means of manipulation.
Just trust the science and yet there have even been recent reports of 11,000
peer-reviewed scientific papers being retracted.
as science has faced an existential crisis.
More than 70% of researchers have tried and failed to reproduce another scientist's experiment.
And if you want to truly understand the extent to which science is fabricated, you can check out
The Real Anthony Fauci by RFK Jr.
is this book that
actually claims the entire HIV industry was fabricated.
to fund Dr. Fauci's little political games and corporate interests in order to fund the money
to his friends what matters more in this world.
isn't the data but instead it's having some big influential celebrity
Voicing an opinion and whatever that opinion is becomes truth, it becomes fact
So that's why the little computer program you're working on out there, the little app or website or whatever
stupid in your coding is going to be totally ignored and nobody even cares.
You see, what people should do is just relax and sit back like me.
You could work, but you're going to get laid off one way or another.
another Tesla laying off another 7,000 people reportedly starting in June.
What these companies do is first they hire you.
And then they burn and churn, they threaten to fire you.
making work evenings and weekends, extracting maximum value, milking you for everything that you've got.
and then you get fired one way or another in the end and you lose the equity that you may have been building
that company.
They just say hey you know what we don't need you anymore sorry.
Bye.
And the other thing I think...
these tech companies have realized is that with the COVID era and all of the remote work,
Companies realize that not only can they do remote work, but that they can actually just outsource
all workers all together to third world countries where people are cheaper and people work harder.
Americans especially can't compete.
to hire Americans anymore.
The American workforce is expensive.
self-entitled, lazy, fat, quite literally.
and they tend to be social activists.
Who wants that on their team?
I suppose if you're truly foolish, you could even go to...
college and get yourself into massive student debt.
and then try to dig yourself out of that debt through decades of wage slavery in a 95-cubicle
And maybe, just maybe you might break even or even turn a small profit.
before you find yourself old and withered away from a sedentary lifestyle.
may be sick and diseased and having your savings
destroyed with runaway inflation and ultimately discarded and replaced by
AI or outsourced workers as companies burn and churn through their employees.
I think there's just no more opportunity.
in the traditional 9-5 world.
And so that's why
I've decided to just entirely stop trying to be productive.
in late stage capitalism, which is where
we're at now, there is no actual productivity left anymore.
It's a zero-sum game and there's only one way left for anybody to make
money around here and this good old-fashioned classic and this is my favorite scamming
And so we have fees, convenience fees, tips, tips upon tips.
20% tips, 30% tips.
Hey, just give more.
In Venting Wars, there are GoFundMes and charity donations for
fake diseases like people pretending they have cancer.
Dark patterns everywhere.
Notice how every single iPad app is a monthly recurring subscription.
There are credit card fees everywhere, speeding tickets.
for even going 5 mph over their speed limit.
actually protecting the roads but not making anyone safer.
It's just there to collect money for the government.
That's what they're doing out there.
Taxes going up without any apparent upgrades to any of the infrastructure you've got home
hospital bill scams, insurance bill scams, HOA housing bill scams.
Like with the HOA, sometimes you're paying thousands of dollars and there's no service.
There's not even a yard, there's no amenities, nothing at all.
What is this HOA fee for?
Oh yeah right, they're scamming you.
And you have to remember all of this is because
where in a stagnant economy, there is zero productivity.
whatever you're doing out there for your line of work, just gotta keep in mind, it's not productive.
And if you want more proof that there's just no
No more work to be done and we have reached a stage of zero productivity.
Just look at Apple.
which is completely one of the largest buybacks in history where they had so much excessive cash.
They didn't know what to do with the money, they couldn't find anything worth investing in.
nothing worth research and development in.
They didn't need to hire anybody, they just took that money and bought back
their own stock.
And I'll tell you what they probably should have done with that excess cash is
just buy some bitcoin with it.
There was another company, some medical company, similar scientific which
They took their cash reserves, put into Bitcoin, their stock went up 28% right away.
When we take a look at the overall tech landscape,
the metaverse failed, web 3 failed, you know these could have been
entire massive revolutionary industries that would have employed
Huge swaths of Americans out there, the whole industry was shut down by regulation.
And so after that, we were eventually thrown back into
the web 2.0 era, a blast from the past of mobile apps
over-saturated, tired old apps.
And there's just no more opportunity there, not only are consumers tired of these apps
vegetating on videos already, but all of the APIs and data.
that these third-party apps would traditionally have relied on in order to provide services are now being
shut down and blocked off for AI.
No company wants to release their AI data anymore to anybody
And so nowadays, almost every single API is shut down and siloed off from one another.
to prevent the AI data scraping, thus incapacitating most third-party apps in the process.
Now some people are going to say, well, there's AI at least, right?
There was a recent tweet by Meta's chief AI scientist who said, don't work on LLM.
This is in the hands of large companies.
There's nothing you can bring to the table.
Maybe instead you should work on some other next-gen AI system that lifts some limitation of LLM
So I guess there's some opportunities.
opportunity there if you think you can bring about the next revolution of AI.
Maybe get a PhD in that first.
Another major headwind in tech worth mentioning has been de-globalization.
where the world is starting to split into separate factions.
Whereas in the past, tech companies had global reach.
Today, most tech companies have had their reach actively being blocked by other countries.
Russia, China, the BRICS nations have raised their own digital
firewalls, tech companies are just not as profitable.
as they used to be as they're now becoming domestic local companies.
In conclusion, some errors are just bad.
Sometimes you just can't make money.
The rich get richer, the poor get poorer.
Tech is done.
The STEM degree is done.
Merit is done.
where nowadays working is like swimming upstream against the inflation and printing machine.
I recently read the Bitcoin standard and what I came to realize is that
when the US came off the gold standard in 1971.
It was quite the devious move actually where I threw that.
They unlock the full value of the US GDP and household economy.
for taxation purposes.
So whereas in the past all they could do was raise taxes but
your personal property would always have value.
It was backed by a goat.
Now they could just print and inflate all of the US GDP value away.
And so now we are paying off our debt by issuing more debt.
with the U.S.
national debt rising by $1 trillion every 100 days in some death cycle.
So given that, how do we succeed in this world?
Well, first off, if you're working some 9 to 5 wage slavery.
job maybe you should just stop it's a total waste of your life but I have three
suggestions.
Number one is entrepreneurship.
Now of course you're going to say, well not everyone can be an entrepreneur or you weren't all made to be one, but you know what?
People said the same thing about programmers as well.
Everyone can be a programmer, and yet nowadays, everyone's a programmer.
We just adapted to that.
And so in the future, everyone may have to become an entrepreneur as well.
You know, we're not talking about some like Elon Musk, Jeff Bezos caliber entrepreneur, but
Even small business owners, hustlers, grifters,
blue collar workers like gardeners, handymen, dog walkers, they all qualify as entrepreneurs.
actually and many of them make more than some software engineer.
especially the laid off ones, and they're probably under less stress and have more free time as well.
Now this may be difficult especially for those who have spent the majority of their childhood
to be some 9-5 wage slave indoctrinated into the school education system.
And even more weirdly, many of these people, perhaps including you yourself,
still aspire to be some top tier wage slave.
climbing that corporate ladder in order to achieve some fancy title or that corner office
wear that suit, but you've just got to give that dream up if you want to succeed in the new world.
The second consideration is we're no longer in
knowledge economy or anything science-based.
We are in an attention economy.
media-based.
Most apps these days have already
been replaced by influencers, content, video.
And I'll tell you something, AI is not going to succeed as well in my opinion.
in the world of influencers because fundamentally there's no right or wrong answer.
we don't live in an objective world and so the right answer
is whatever your favorite influencer or content creator tells you is the right answer.
Whatever they tell you to buy, how to live, how to think, that is what you will listen to.
You're not going to listen to ChatGPT.
I mean, when you think about it, nobody even pays for ChatGPT Premium, they're starting to give that stuff away.
stuff out for free.
And then the last suggestion, consider taking up a job as a Bitcoiner.
Hey, it's not easy and it's not for everyone to dime in hand and huddle all day long and it can be pretty tiring.
and tough boring work, but it turns out the more you study Bitcoin,
The more serious you become at it, the more you're willing to hold, and the higher your profits will be too.
or your losses.
All right.
Anyways, I gotta get back to work.
Got some more huddling to do.
See you in the next one.